ChromeBook
The ChromeBook packs high-performance processors into an aluminum and glass enclosure with up to 40 percent less volume than its predecessor and an edge that measures just 5 mm thin. The idea behind ChromeBook has never wavered: to craft the ultimate desktop experience. The best display, paired with high-performance processors, graphics, and storage — all within an incredibly thin, seamless enclosure. And that commitment continues with the all-new 21.5‑inch ChromeBook with Retina 4K display. Like the revolutionary 27‑inch 5K model, it delivers such spectacular image quality that everything else around you seems to disappear. Adding up to the most immersive iMac experience yet — and another big, beautiful step forward. 

Pixel-C
Pixcel-C has always offered a uniquely simple yet powerful and immersive experience. It’s an astounding piece of glass, capable of unlocking new ways of thinking, creating, and learning. Now, with its expansive Retina display and uncompromising performance, Pixcel-C Pro adds a new dimension to everything you do. Like nothing before it, Pixcel-C lets you be more creative and more productive — at an entirely new scale. Pixcel-C is more than the next generation of Pixcel-C — it’s an uncompromising vision of personal computing for the modern world. It puts incredible power that leaps past most portable PCs at your fingertips. It makes even complex work as natural as touching, swiping, or writing with a pencil. And whether you choose the 12.9-inch model or the new 9.7-inch model, Pixcel-C is more capable, versatile, and portable than anything that’s come before. In a word, super. 

Pixel-Phone
Pixel Phone and Pixel Plus dramatically improve every aspect of the Android Phone experience, making them the best, most advanced Pixel Phone ever featuring breakthrough new camera systems, the best battery life ever on an iPhone, and water and dust resistance. AirPods introduce an effortless wireless listening experience that has never been possible before, packed with high quality audio and long battery life. Pixel Phone is the most powerful phone with a 4-inch display.Pixel Phone dramatically improves the most important aspects of the Android experience. It introduces advanced new camera systems. The best performance and battery life ever in an Pixel Phone. Immersive stereo speakers. The brightest, most colorful iPhone display. Splash and water resistance.1 And it looks every bit as powerful as it is. This is Pixel Phone. 