Thanks for Shopping !

We appreciate the fact that you like to buy the cool stuff we   build. We also want to make sure you have a rewarding experience while you're exploring, evaluating, and purchasing our products, whether   you&rsquo;re in an Apple Retail Store, on apple.com, through the Apple Store App, or on the phone with the Apple Contact Center. (To make it visually   easier on both of us, we&rsquo;ll refer to these entities as the "Apple Store" in this policy.)

As with any shopping experience, there are terms and conditions that   apply to transactions at an Apple Store. We'll be as brief as our   attorneys will allow. The main thing to remember is that by placing an   order or making a purchase at an Apple Store, you agree to the terms set   forth below along with Apple's Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.